It is often said that if we dream in a foreign language, it's a sign that we are making progress in learning that language.
人们常说，如果我们用外语做梦，这标志着我们在学习该语言上取得了进步。
But is it true?
但这是真的吗？
Before we can look at multilingual dreams, first we need to look at sleep.
在研究多语言梦境之前，我们首先需要了解睡眠。
The link between sleep and language can be applied to how we learn any language, including our mother tongue.
睡眠和语言之间的联系适用于我们如何学习任何语言，包括我们的母语。
Even adults still learn about one new word every two days in their first language, but, if we are going to have a firm grasp of that new word, we need to link it to our existing knowledge.
即使是成年人，每两天仍能学会大约一个母语新词，但要想牢固掌握那个新词，我们需要将其与现有知识联系起来。
And in order to do that, we 'need to have some sleep', says Gareth Gaskell, a psychology professor at the University of York.
约克大学心理学教授加雷思·加斯克尔说，为了做到这一点，我们"需要睡上一觉"。
It's during sleep that the integration of old and new knowledge happens.
新旧知识的整合正是在睡眠中发生的。
At night, one part of our brain – the hippocampus – takes whatever new information it soaked up in the day, and passes it on to other parts of the brain to be stored.
夜间，我们大脑的一部分——海马体——会接收它在白天吸收的任何新信息，并将其传递给大脑的其他部分进行存储。
The role that dreams play in this night-time learning process is still being studied, but 'it's entirely possible that during multilingual dreams, the brain is trying to connect two languages', says Marc Züst, researcher at the University Hospital of Old Age Psychiatry and Psychotherapy in Bern, Switzerland.
梦境在这一夜间学习过程中扮演的角色仍处于研究阶段，但瑞士伯尔尼大学老年精神病学与心理治疗医院的研究员马克·聚斯特表示，"在多语言梦境中，大脑完全有可能是在尝试连接两种语言"。
So having multilingual dreams could mean that our brain is trying to master a new word or phrase, for example, but it could also have an emotional significance.
因此，做多语言梦可能意味着我们的大脑正试图掌握一个新单词或短语，但也可能具有情感上的意义。
Danuta Gabryś-Barker, a professor of psycholinguistics at the University of Silesia in Poland, suggests that multilingual dreams can express 'fears and desires' around learning a foreign language, including the wish to be a native-like speaker or to be accepted within a certain community.
波兰西里西亚大学心理语言学教授达努塔·加布里什-巴克认为，多语言梦境可以表达围绕学习外语的"恐惧和愿望"，包括希望像母语者一样说话，或被某个特定群体接纳的愿望。
We clearly still have a lot to learn about multilingual dreams, but one thing seems certain: if you're trying to learn a new language, you should definitely sleep on it.
关于多语言梦境，我们显然还有很多东西要了解，但有一件事似乎是肯定的：如果你想学习一门新语言，绝对应该睡上一觉再做决定。